William J. Walls Papers
William J. Walls Papers
1957-1969
Walls, William Jacob, 1885-1975.
6.0 linear ft.
Papers of the African-American bishop of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church. Correspondence, speeches and sermons, photographs, and clippings.
148733
Biographical History
Bishop William J. Walls, African American churchman and author, graduated from Livingstone College and Hood Seminary. He did graduate work at Columbia University, and received an advanced degree from the University of Chicago.
Walls was an active member of the African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church, originally formed in 1796 in New York City in response to discrimination against blacks in the regular Methodist Church. Walls' home congregation was Thomas Memorial AME Zion in Watertown, New York, long known as an anti-slavery church; notable members included Harriet Tubman, Sojourner Truth, Katherine Harris,Jermaine Loguen, and Frederick Douglass.
Among his other duties, Walls served as senior bishop and secretary of the Board of Bishops and as chairman of the Board of Christian Education, Home and Church, and participated in Christian Education conventions on the denominational, national, international, and world levels. He was a member of the Central Committee of the World Council of Churches, the executive committee of the World Council of Methodism, and the General Assembly and General Board of the National Council of the Churches of Christ, and was the ecumenical spokesman for Zion Methodism.
In addition to his church activities, Wall was active in the National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (NAACP), serving on the Board of Directors and as vice president. He also found time to write, producing a biography of Joseph Charles Price, founder and first president of Livingstone College, and a definitive history of AME Zion entitled The African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church: Reality of the Black Church (1974).
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The William J. Walls Papers consists of correspondence-subject files and two later additions which have not been integrated. Correspondence-subject files are subdivided chronologically. 1981 additions consists of books, correspondence, clippings, personal memorabilia (will, etc) and writings, as well as more than fifty years of the Official Journals of the Zion Church. 1983 additions consists of a single typescript for Prophets of Freedom by Bishop W.J. Walls.
Arrangement of the Collection
Files are arranged chronologically and within that alphabetically (with some aberrations). Note that box numbers are not unique; please specify accession and box number when requesting items.
Subject and Genre Headings
African Americans; Church and clergy; New York State; Walls, William Jacob, 1885-1975.; African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church.; African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church -- Clergy.; African American clergy.; African American Methodists.; African Americans -- Biography.; Clergy -- United States.; Methodists -- United States.; Sermons, American.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Photographs.; Sermons.; Speeches (documents); Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Inventory
- Correspondence-subject files, ca. 1958
  - "A General" (Box 1)
    Abbott, Edward P.
    Ackerman, A.A.
    Acolatse, Cephas L.
    Adjahoe, Juanita
    Aggrey, Rose D.
    Allen, Frank M. (4)
    Allen, J. Roy L. (2)
    Alstork, C. Donald, Sr.
    American Bible Society
    Andrews, D.W.
    Armstrong, J.D.
    Atkins, F.L.
    Atlanta University
    Audrey, Franklin A.
  - AME Zion Departments (Box 1)
  - American Bible Society (Box 1)
  - "B General" (Box 1)
    Ballard, C.H.
    Barnes, Christine
    Barnes, Otho W.
    Beck, William Tecumseh
    Bell, A.C. (3)
    Belton, J.A.
    Bennett, Alice R.D. (2)
    Bennett, Leroy J. (2)
    Bennett, Lucile
    Bess, Hunter B. (8)
    Bethel AME Zion Church
    Bishop, Shelton Hale
    Blackwell, George H.
    Brockelt, Julien
    Brooks, George A.
    Brooks, T.H. (2)
    Brown, F.R.
    Brown, Ruth
    Brumley, Edward
    Buie, George (3)
    Burruss, Ann L.
  - Barber Camp (Box 1)
  - Board of Bishops: Correspondence (Box 1)
  - "C General" (Box 1)
    Canavati, Saliba K.
    Cannady, M.A.
    Canty, J. Carl
    Carr, Robert K.
    Carrington, W.O. (2)
    Carter, Cordelia
    Catledge, J. Van
    Cauthen, J.D.
    Cave, Margaret
    Churchill, Frank E.
    Clark, L.C.
    Clark, James
    Clarke, E.O.
    Clayton, Robert L. II
    Clinton Junior College
    Cochrane, William G. (2)
    Cofield, Jacob P. (2)
    Coleman, C.C. (3)
    Coleman, S.C.
    Connectional Council & Board of Bishops Programs
    Lovallo, Connors & Matusick
    Cooper, W.A.
    The Pittsburgh Courier (6)
    Cuthbertson, Reverend M.R. (2)
  - Camp Dorothy Walls (Box 1)
  - Church Federation of Greater Chicago (Box 1)
  - Circular (Box 1)
  - "D General" (Box 1)
    Dancy, John C.
    Daniels, Theodore W.
    Davidson, M.E.
    Davis, R.W.
    DeBerry, P.L.
    Dexter, E.B.
    Dixie, Thomas A.
    Draft, Ira Lee
    Dulles, John Foster
    Duncan, Samuel E. (5)
    Dunston, Alfred S.
  - "E General" (Box 1)
    Eastern Clergy Bureau (2)
    Eichelberger, James W. (5)
    English, Jeanette (3)
    Evans, Carrie Slack
  - "F General" (Box 1)
    Fernandez, R.W.
    Flowers, J.G.
    Ford, Charles (2)
    Foster, Richard A.G. (4)
    Francis, D. Oliver (2)
    French, J.H. (2)
    Fuller, Albert L.
    Funderburk, J. R.
  - Foreign Letter and Stamps (Box 1)
  - "G General" (Box 1)
    Gerald, Joseph S.
    Germany, Freeman
    Gillian, W.M.
    Gladden, J.D. (2)
    Glover, O.L.
    Goldstein, Arthur I.
    Goode, E.L.
    Grady, Nathaniel T., Jr.
    Grant, Alonzo C.
    Green, Elizabeth Lee
    Gullette, Ralph W.
  - "H General" (Box 1)
    Hadley, Marion M.
    Hall, Emma
    Hall, Henry L. (2)
    Hardge, Arthur L. (4)
    Hardge, E.S. Sr.
    Hardge, E.S. Jr. (2)
    Hardy, Lenora (5)
    Hardy, Ruth
    Harper, Addie (2)
    Harris, Edward C.
    Harris, Leon D.
    Harris, R.J.
    Hatwood, Edgar L.
    Hawkins, Mary
    Henderson, W.T. (2)
    Hill, C.L.
    Hill, George J. (3)
    Himphie, James
    Hinds, Hewley E.
    Hogan, E.L. (4)
    Hogan, William D. (2)
    Hogan, William D. Jr.
    Hoggard, J. Clinton "Holly Knollers"
    Holmes, John W.
    Holmes, J.H.
    Holt, Ivan Lee (3)
    Holton, Walter
    Hopkins, Samuel L.
    Hoskins, Fred
    Houston, Isaac Lewis (3)
    Howcott, Chas.
    Hunnicutt, A.C.
    Hunt, Wilma Mae
    Hunter, F.B.
    Hunter, G.W. (3)
    Hunter, R.T. (2)
    Hyslop, Ralph Douglas
  - "I General" (Box 1)
    Illinois Institute of Technology
    Inniss, Charles N. (2)
    Irwin, William A.
    Ithaca Loan Finance
  - Inter-Church Center (Box 1)
  - Invitations (Box 1)
  - "J General" (Box 1)
    Jackson, Belvie H. Jr.
    Jackson, E. Franklin (3)
    Jackson, T.S. (2)
    Jackson, William W.
    Jarrett, R.H.
    Jenkins, J. Dallas
    Jernagin, W.H.
    Johnson, Elsie M.
    Johnson, Ernestine
    Johnson, J.A. Babington
    Johnson, John H.
    Johnson, Joyce
    Jones, A.
    Jones, Frank E. (4)
    Jones, Janie C.
    Jones, N.V. (4)
    Jones, Richard P.
    Jones, William H.
  - "K General" (Box 1)
    Karefa-Smart, Rena
    Keaton, H.A. (2)
    Kendall, C.R.
    Kennedy, E.C.
    Kennedy, John F.
    Khan, Abiel H. (3)
    King, Martin Luther, Jr. (2)
    Kirnon, H.H. (3)
    Kleinwald, Arthur
    Kost, Bertha (2)
  - "L General" (Box 1)
    Lakeville AME Zion Church
    Laws, George (2)
    Leak, Hattie M.
    Leake, George J.
    Linder, M.P.
    Lineback, C.L. (2)
    Littlejohn, M.L. (3)
    Lockhart, Elizabeth
    Lockhart, Devera J. (2)
    Logan, Bert H.
    London, Georgia
    Long, Charles H. (2)
    Lovell, Dr. Walter R. (2)
    Lowe, F.I.
  - Livingstone College
  - "M General" (Box 1)
    Marguis Company
    Marsh, Marion (3)
    Massey, John F.
    Mathews, Fannie
    May, Aurthur E. (6)
    May, Margaret J. (3)
    Mays, Benjamin E.
    Michael, E.R.
    Michael, Margaret
    Miller, Edward
    Miller, George Mason
    Miller, Howard W.
    Miller, Mason
    Mills, Florence R.
    Monroe, Irene
    Montgomery, Leroy J. (2)
    Moore, Eleanor
    Moore, Ercelle Harmon
    Moore, Hugh
    Moore, Lula (2)
    Mooreland, Sallie V.
    Morgan, Eugene E., Jr.
    Morris, A. P.
    Mother AME Zion Church
    Mullen Vester L.
    Murdock, John D., Sr.
    Murtagh, John M.
  - "Mc General" (Box 1)
    McCouley, Darnell C.
    McDew, Gladys
    McDougal, T.C. (2)
    McGuire, P.E. (7)
    McKinney, Carnes (3)
    McMillan, J.Q.
    McMillan, J.T.
    McMulle, M.L.
    McMurray, G.W. (2)
  - "N General" (Box 1)
    Neal, William J. (2)
    New York Council of Churches
    Nochols, D. ward
    Nitchman, Alvin F.
    Noble, Mazie (3)
    Nooe, Roger T.
    Norment, C.E.
    Norville, H.B.
    Norwood, W.S.
    Nurse, Herbert
  - N.A.A.C.P. (Box 1)
  - National Council of Churches, USA (Box 1)
  - New England Conference (Box 1)
  - New York Conference (Box 1)
  - Newspaper Clippings (Box 1)
  - "O General" (Box 1)
    O’Dell, L. Howard
    Oliver, Douglas and Dorothy
    Owens, George
  - "P General" (Box 1)
    Paris, William A. (6)
    Parks, Cornelia (3)
    Pater, Alan F.
    Patterson, Gladys
    Perdue, Jeanette (2)
    Perry, A.A. (2)
    Pharr, Pauline and David
    Philip, P.P. (3)
    Pierce, A.L. (2)
    Pierre, Maurice (9)
    Plack, Carl R.
    Poe, William M.
    Pollard, John H. (2)
    Powe, Thomas M.
    Powell, Edna
    Prattis, P.L.
    The President’s Committee
    Price, J.A.
    Priester, Marcus J.
    Primas, Brennan Keys
    Proctor, Emory C.
  - Photographs (Box 1)
  - Programs and Bulletins (Box 1)
  - Public Relations/Press Matters (Box 1)
  - Publicity (Box 1)
  - "Q General" (Box 1)
    Quick, Joseph F.
  - "R General" (Box 1)
    Railroad (2)
    Redditte, B.
    Reed, Samuel B. (2)
    Reid, Leon A., Jr.
    Remsen, Oscar Jeremiah
    Rice, Willa Mae
    Rich, C.B.
    Richards, Hilda
    Richardson, Louis M.
    Riddick, T.J.
    Roan, Homer S.
    Roberts, Clarence H.
    Robeson, B.C. (3)
    Robeson, Francis C.
    Robinson, Dorothy
    Robinson, Georgia
    Robinson, Jackie (7)
    Robinson, Laberta (2)
    Robinson, M.B.
    Robinson, Major
    Rollins, Mary
    Rudd, Daisy E.
    Rudd, M.S. (9)
    Ruffin, Jacob C. (3)
  - Race and Human Relations (Box 1)
  - "S General" (Box 1)
    Schrag, Oswald O.
    Schultz, S.W. (2)
    Seagle, A.D.
    Seay, S.S.
    Service, Cleon O.
    Servis, Harry H. (5)
    Shaw, Benjamin G. (3)
    Shaw, Herbert Bell
    Sherrill, Richard W. (2)
    Shufford, Adrian L., Jr.
    Shufford, Adrian L., Sr.
    Silas, Eulalia L.
    Siler, Lee Clinton
    Sisco, Ruth E.
    Slade, W.W.
    Smith, J.F.
    Smith Joseph Aggrey
    Smith, M.M. (2)
    Smith, Percy, Jr.
    Smith, Percy, Sr.
    Smith, William M. (3)
    Southern Conference Educational Fund, Inc.
    Spears, A.E.
    St. Clair, V. Loma (3)
    Stewart, James E. (9)
    Stewart, W.A.
    Straud, Hazeline R.
    Stringfield, John A. (2)
  - "T General" (Box 1)
    Tate, Slaughter and Elizabeth M.
    Taylor, L. Barbara
    Thomas, Carl Alan (2)
    Thombs, Leo L.
    Thompson, J.W.
    Thorton, Mabel
    Tiemeyer, Raymond
    Torrence, C.L.
    Trent, William J. Jr. (6)
    Tsapis, Stanley
    Tulans, Victor J.
    Turner, G.R. (2)
    Turner, Smith (3)
  - Telegrams (Box 1)
  - Tubman, Harriet (home) (Box 1)
  - "U General" (Box 1)
    University of Chicago
  - "V General" (Box 1)
    Van Dusan, Henry P.
    Van Horn, Olive O.
    Van Oppen & Co., Inc. (2)
    Van Putten, C.L.
    Vantage Press (Arthur Kleinwald) (4)
    Varner, Sammie Lee
    Vogel, Edward
  - "W General" (Box 1)
    Wactor, Hildred H. (2)
    Wales, Wellington
    Walker, William O. (2)
    Walters, Zoe A. (5)
    Ward, Milton N. (7)
    Ward, Paul L.D.
    Warfield, Vernice
    Waters, V.B.
    Watkins, Johnsie W.
    Watson, M.R.G.
    Watson, Robert M., Jr. (2)
    Welcome, Verda F. (2)
    Weller, S.W. (2)
    Wells, I.J.K.
    Wells, J.J.
    Wells, Rudolph L.
    West, A.B.
    Westlehoff, Harold
    Wetterhahn, Ross A. (2)
    White, Luther L.
    White, Reid R.
    Whitfield, Alphonso
    Who’s Who in America
    Wilberforce University Carnegie Library
    Williams, C.C.
    Williams, Laura M.
    Williams, Sayde J.
    Wisdom, David P.
    Wolins, LeRoy
    Woodhouse, Enoch O. (2)
    Woodhouse, Gertrude Tyler
    Works, David A.
    Wornom, Herman E.
  - Walls, W. J. (personal data) (Box 1)
  - Western New York (Box 1)
  - Western North Carolina Conference (Box 1)
  - World Council of Churches (Box 1)
  - World Methodist Council (Box 1)
  - World Sunday School Convention, 1958 (Box 1)
  - Writing and Addresses (Box 1)
  - "X,Y,Z" (No contents) (Box 1)
- Correspondence-subject files, ca. 1959-1960
  - "A General" (Box 1)
    Acolatse, Cephas Leonard
    Adams, Bert
    Adams, Oscar W., Jr.
    Adjahoe, Juanita A.
    African American Students Foundation, Inc.
    Agaard, James A.
    Alba, Clarence A.
    Allen, F.M. (6)
    Allen, J. Roy L. (3)
    Allen, JoAnne
    Allen, Yorke, Jr.
    Anderson, Felix S.
    Anderson, Herman L. (3)
    Andrews, N.B. (2)
    Ardrey, William Carleton
    Armstrong, J.D. (2)
    Arnaold, Irene M.
    Arnold, James A.
    Atkins, F.L. (2)
  - Appreciation – Thank You Expressions, 1959-1960 (Box 1)
    Christian Education (Dr. J.W. Eichelberger)
    Church Extension (D.W. Andrews)
    Church School Literature (Dr. J. Van Catledge)
    Connectional Council
    Evangelism (Dr. W.S. Dacons)
    Finance Department
    Foreign Missions – Missionary Seer (Dr. J.C. Hoggard)
    General Secretary – Auditor (Mrs. Alstork)
    Home Missions – Pension Relief (Dr. A.P. Morris)
    Hymnal Commission – Hymnal Matters (Printing)
    Public Relations (Mr. Alexander Barnes)
    Publishing House (Dr. L.L. Boyd)
    Quarterly review – History (Dr. David H. Bradley)
    Star of Zion (Dr. W.R. Lovell)
  - "B General" (Box 2)
    Babington – Johnson, J.A.
    Bagby, John A. (3)
    Baker, Vincent S.
    Barnes, Otto W.
    Batson, Frances L.
    Battle, George C. (2)
    Battle, J.L. (2)
    Beal, James (2)
    Bell, A.C. (8)
    Bell, Elizabeth (2)
    Bell, R.R.
    Belton, J.A. (4)
    Bennett, Alice R.W. (2)
    Bennett, L. Roy
    Bess, Hunter B. (4)
    Blackwell, William Allen (3)
    Blakely, F.R.
    Board of Bishops
    Bonner, Harrison D.
    Borden, Anna
    Bradley, Ray W., Jr.
    Brandon, Mack, Jr.
    Braxton, Gloria (2)
    Brockett, J.H.
    Brooks, Arthur E.
    Brooks, G. Alexander
    Brooks, John W.
    Brown, Harriet
    Brown, J.C. (2)
    Brown, Naomi
    Brunner, Lillian T.
    Buford, K.L.
    Buie, G.C., Jr.
    Burke, Samuel J. (2)
    Burnett, Granville A. (2)
    Burruss, Ann
    Byrd, Thelma
    Anderson, F.S.
  - Brown, W.C. (Box 2)
  - Cauthen, J.D. (Box 2)
  - Hillard, W.A. (Box 2)
  - Jones, R.L. (Box 2)
  - Lartey, S. Dorme (Box 2)
  - Medford, H.T. (Box 2)
  - Pope, D.C. (Box 2)
  - Shaw, H.B. (Box 2)
  - Slade, W.W. (Box 2)
  - Smith, W.M. (Box 2)
  - Stewart, W.A. (Box 2)
  - Tucker, C.E. (Box 2)
  - Bishops – Correspondence, 1959-1960
    African Methodist Episcopal Zion Church
    Joseph V. Baker Associates, Inc.
    Board of Bishops (19)
    Murray, J. Kenneth (2)
    National Council of the Churches of Christ (10)
    Rockefeller, Nelson A.
    Sky Pilots of America and International, Inc.
    United Negro College Fund, Inc.
    John Westley A.M.E. Zion Church
  - Bishops – Programs, 1959-1960 (Box 2)
  - "C General" (Box 2)
    Cacter, Cordelia
    Calhoun, R.L.
    Carman, Harry J.
    Carrington, Susie O.
    Carrington, W.E. (5)
    Carson, B. Leon
    Chambers, Andrew W.
    Chandler, Charles
    Channel Press, Inc.
    Chapman, Daniel A.
    Clarke, E.O. (2)
    Clarke, Vardrienne
    Clement, Rufus E. (2)
    Clement, S.I.
    Coffey, Josephine C. (2)
    Coker, Naomi Hayes (2)
    Coleman, Allestis (2)
    Collins, J.G.
    Cooper, Georgia Payne
    Cooper, Izetta
    Council, Richard A.
    Crawford, Percy B.
    Crumlin, James A.
    Curtis, J.C. (3)
    Cuthbertson, M.R. (3)
  - Circular – Incoming (Box 2)
  - Circular – Outgoing (Box 2)
  - "D General" (Box 2)
    Davies, J. Kenneth (2)
    Davis, Jerome
    Dill, William T. (2)
    Dolley, W.K.
    Donald, Laura A. (2)
    Douglas, Mary B.
    Downing, L.C. (2)
    Duncan, Julia B.
    Dunston, Alfred G., Jr. (3)
    Durant, W.A.C. (2)
    Durham, J.E.
  - "E General" (Box 2)
    Early, Estella
    Elliot, Anne
    Ellis, Mattie F.
    Elmore, Lyllian G. (2)
    English, Jeanette and Walter
    Ezell, W.J. (2)
  - "F General" (Box 2)
    Farrar, Alice G.
    Fawcett, Crystal Burd (3)
    Fergusin, (Mrs.)
    Ferrini, Lindo
    Feuster, Hattie
    Fiawoo, F.K.
    Findley, J.W.
    Finkley, J.H.
    Florian, Frank B. (3)
    Floyd, Minnie L.
    Foggie, Charles H.
    Ford, Clemson C.
    Foster, Richard A.G. (9)
    Fox, Frederick
    Fox, Rosa
    Francis, Martha B. (3)
    Frasier, M.W.
    Frazier, William H.
    Freeman, Sue B.
    French, J.H.
    Fulgham, Elbert M. (4)
    Funderburk, J.R. (2)
  - Foreign Letters and Stamps (Box 2)
  - First District Youth Conferences (First Epis. District)
    - New England Conference (First Epis. District) (Box 2)
    - New York Conference (First Epis. District) (Box 2)
    - Western New York Conference (First Epis. District) (Box 2)
    - Western North Carolina annual Conference (First Epis. District) (Box 2)
  - "G General" (Box 2)
    Gantt, Edward W. (2)
    Garrison, Norman T.
    Genzlinger, Dorothea
    Germany, Freeman (2)
    Gisbon, A.N. (2)
    Gladden, Mary J.
    Gore, Jethro
    Graham, Tecumseh X. (3)
    Green, Elizabeth Lee (2)
    Green, Samson
    Green, Soforo
    Greene, S.L.
    Grier, Mary L.
    Gullette, Ralph W. (4)
    Gunn, Sinclara
  - General Conference Correspondence, 1960 (Box 2)
  - "H General" (Box 2)
    Hardge, Arthur L. (3)
    Hardge, Clara E.
    Hardge, Elias S. (6)
    Hardy, Lenora B. (2)
    Harper, A. (Sister)
    Harper, A.D. (Reverend)
    Harrington, Frances
    Harris, Arthaniel E.
    Harris, Jeardine N.
    Harris, R.J., Jr.
    Harris, R.J., Sr.
    Harrison, Nina Beatrice Jones
    Hart, N.E. (2)
    Hayes, E.W.
    Hazzard, Samuel Harrison
    Hemphill, James T.
    Henderson, William T. (5)
    Henry, Hayward (2)
    Herndon, george
    Hewitt, Annie
    Hewitt, Minnie
    Hicks, Martha
    Hill, Ellaleon C.
    Hilliard, William A. (2)
    Hogan, E.L. (2)
    Hogan, B.D.
    Hogans William D.
    Hoggard, Eva
    Hoggard, J.C.
    Hoggard, Symra T.
    Homes, John W. (2)
    Hooker, William J. (2)
    Horrington, Emily M.
    Houston, I.L.
    Howard, Alice
    Howard, Lawrence W.
    Howard, Louise
    Howard, Theodore (2)Hudgins, Mary
    Hunter, F.B. (2)
    Hunter, George Washington (3)
    Hunter, Gladys H.
    Hunter, Lemuel B.
    Hunter, R.I.
    Hunter, R.T. (5)
    Hurl, Helen
    Hurley, M.D.
    Hyatt, Edward L. (2)
    Hyslop, Ralph D.
  - "I General" (Box 2)
    Inniss, Charles (3)
    Irvis, Howard w.
    Isaac, McDonald
    Isaacs, Harold R.
  - Institutions –
    - Camp Barber Memorial (Box 2)
    - Camp Dorothy Walls (Box 2)
    - Clinton Junior College (Box 2)
    - Harriet Tubman Home (Box 2)
    - Hood Seminary (Box 2)
    - Lake Placid Property (Box 2)
    - Livingstone College (Box 2)
    - Livingstone College (President) Dr. S.E. Duncan (Box 2)
    - Lomax-Hannon College (Box 2)
    - Schools and Colleges (Miscellaneous) (Box 2)
  - Inter Church Center (Box 2)
  - Invitations (Box 2)
  - "J General" (Box 2)
    Jackson, Clarence P.
    Jackson, E. Franklin
    Jenkins, J. Dallas (2)
    Jepson, J.C.
    Jerry, Elsie A.
    Jewell, J.W. (4)
    Jiles, W.J.
    Johnson, Andrew
    Johnson, Edward
    Johnson, Frances B.
    Johnson, Joyce (5)
    Johnson, N.J.
    Johnson, Ulysses S.
    Jones, H.C. (3)
    Jones, Mande
    Jones, N.V. (2)
    Jury Commissions of Cooke County
  - K General (Box 2)
    Keaton, S.G.
    Kelly, Adena Z.
    Kilgon, Jackson
    Kindt, Helen F.
    King, Martin Luther, Jr.
    Kinney, Lee
    Kristenson, Kristen (2)
  - "L General" (Box 2)
    Lankford, H. Philbert
    Latimer, E.
    Laws, George W.A. (6)
    Laws, Phillippa (3)
    Leak, Hattie M. (3)
    Lee, R.H. Collins (2)
    Leffage, Anna
    Leibrecht, Walter
    Lenoir, William H.
    Leuis, Daisey
    Leyland, Stanley (2)
    Lomax, Thomas
    Lowe, F. Isaac
    Lusan, F.A.
    Lynum, Mary
  - "M General" (Box 2)
    Mack, B.A. (2)
    Mack, C. Henry (9)
    Mapp, Andrew Wesley (3)
    Marguis, Sarah
    Marshall, Paul
    Martignoni, Carlo V. (2)
    Martin, Margaret K.
    Mason, George
    May, A.E. (3)
    May, Margaret J.
    Mays, Walter David
    Michael, E.R. (3)
    Miller, George Mason (2)
    Miller, Isaac H.
    Miller, John H. (5)
    Miller, W.M.
    Millsap, Lillie
    Milo, Robert McKenzie
    Montgomery, Dabney N.
    Montgomery, Leroy J. (4)
    Moore, J.A. H.
    Morgan, B. Earlene Shaw
    Moses, Felix W.
  - "Mc General" (Box 2)
    McCall, James E. (2)
    McDougal, T.C.
    McCowley, Darnell
    McGuire, Paul (2)
    McKinney, Bessie
    McKinney, Carnes (3) McKinney, Petty D. (7)
    McMillian, J.Q. (2)
    McMullen, M.L.
    McMurrary, G.W.
  - "N General" (Box 2)
    Nathan, Ralph G.
    Neal, W.J.
    Nelson, Judith M.
    Nelson, Rosanna
    New England Deaconess Hospital
    New York Times Book Review
    Newby, Richard L. (3)
    Newsweek Magazine
    Nicholson, Irene
    Nixon, Eva L.
    Nixon, Richard M.
    Nixon, Thoms R.
    Noble, Mazie (2)
    Noe, Robert G.
  - "O General" (Box 2)
    O’Neal, Edmond J.
    O’Neal, W.
  - Organizations
    - African and Foreign (Box 2)
    - American Bible Society (Box 2)
    - Boy Scouts and Girl Scouts, 1960 (Box 2)
    - Church Federation of Greater Chicago (Box 2)
    - Fraternal (Negro) Council of Churches (Box 2)
    - International Society of Christian Endeavor (Box 2)
    - National Association for the Advancement of Colored People (Box 2)
    - Protestant Council of Churches – New York (Box 2)
    - Southern Conference Education Fund, Inc. (Box 3)
    - State & Local Council of Churches (Box 3)
    - White House Conference on Children & Youth (Box 3)
    - World Council on Christian Education & Sunday School Convention (Box 3)
    - World Council of Churches (Box 3)
    - World Methodist Council (Box 3)
  - "P General" (Box 3)
    Pak, Peter (5)
    Paris, Rose
    Paris, William A. (3)
    Parry, Wilbur C.
    Pennington, Catherine S. (2)
    Pennoyer
    Perch, Mary and George (3)
    Perry, R.P.
    Pharr, Adolphus Darius
    Philip, P.P. (2)
    Philipose, A.K.
    Pierce, Alexander Lincoln
    Pierce, I. Benjamin (2)
    Pierce, Cora E.
    Pierce, Suzanne
    Pierre, Maurice
    Pierre, Rosella C.
    Pinkey, Luther
    Pogne, King D.S.
    Potter, William A.
    Powe, Beatrice C.
    Powell, Adam C.
    Pyant, R.L. (2)
    Pyle, Howard
  - Photographs (Box 3)
  - Public Relations – News Articles & Clippings (Box 3)
  - Public Relations – News Clippings – General Conference (Box 3)
  - Public Relations – Programs (Box 3)
  - "Q General" (no contents) (Box 3)
  - "R General" (Box 3)
    Raab, Henry F.
    Randolph, A. Philip (3)
    Rhufin, Fannie H. (2)
    Rice, Willa Mae (2)
    Richards, Hilda (2)
    Riddick, George Edgar
    Riddick, Pauline B.
    Rivers, G. Sims
    Rivers, Terrether P.
    Roan, Homer S. (3)
    Robertson, Chauncey H. (2)
    Robertson, Jack L.
    Robeson, B.C. (5)
    Robinson, A.D. (2)
    Robinson, Ernest A.
    Robinson, Jackie
    Robinson, M.B. (6)
    Rochester, Enoch B. (2)
    Rodney, Rita C. (2)
    Rollins, Mary A. (3)
    Roosevelt Tire Service